(262) 455-1195

LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software developer with 1 year of experience developing web applications in a fast-paced technology startup. Use C#, .NET, and SQL Server to build efficient back-end systems to work with dynamic front-end interfaces using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Able to communicate complex concepts in a simple and effective manner.

SKILLS

•	C#

.NET

Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

SQL (SQL Server, MySQL)

Entity Framework

API Development/Integration

Git

R (data analysis & visualization)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

January 2024 - Present

Low Cost Pet Tech, Co.

- Developed RESTful APIs to consolidate a deprecated database into the existing architecture, resulting
 in improved data integrity and enhanced coverage for over 150,000 customer accounts. Optimized
 system efficiency by offloading messaging tasks, achieving a 10% reduction in server load during peak
 hours.
- Integrated third-party APIs, including Google Maps, Radar, American Kennel Club (AKC Reunite),
 Homebase, and Kickbox, into new and existing software solutions.
- Enhanced software performance by using various data structures, including XML & JSON.
- Assisted in communicating key technical concepts and project plans to company executives.

Software Development Intern

September 2023 – January 2024

Low Cost Pet Tech, Co.

 Created a company-wide inventory management system from the ground up, improving efficiency and accuracy in inventory tracking using C# with .NET, Entity Framework, and SQL Server.

Business Owner

January 2021 - July 2023

SLC Vintage Goods LLC

- Co-founded online vintage furniture company with avg. of 93% YoY revenue growth since inception.
- Used HTML and CSS to develop company website: slcvintagegoods.github.io

Graduate Research Fellow

August 2018 - December 2020

University of Utah & Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory

 Used R to analyze, process, and visualize data to conduct original research in geophysics. Published sample: Figure 3 in https://sd.copernicus.org/articles/25/35/2019/

EDUCATION

University of Utah – M.S., Geophysics

August 2018 – December 2020

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee – B.S., Geosciences

January 2014 - May 2018